Rajat Dhiman

Hayward, CA

Contact Number: +1(510) 203-8942 E-mail:rdsocials113@outlook.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajatdhiman3/

Professional Summary

Dedicated technical program manager with 7+ years of experience leading OEM NPI in EMS space delivering product lines such as NVDIMM, CXL, DRAM, SSD, AI Edge servers from cradle to grave. 5+ years of experience for Hardware and Software development and bench-marking experience and experience managing cross functional and multi-national teams. MS in Industrial and Systems Engineering.

Artificial Intelligence, Electronics Manufacturing, Bench-marking, Agile, Scrum, Team and Technical Leadership, Design and Process Engineering, Communication, Continuous improvement, JIRA, Confluence, Business Applications (MS Excel, MS Word)

Experience

Technical Program Manager

Jun. 2022 - Present

Uniaen Corporation

Newark, CA

- Delivered and lead 4 product development cycles from concept to completion and introduced AI product line within the organization, with a total of 12 successful products launched from concept to completion
- Fully owned and managed New Product Introduction and Build pipelines for OEM EMS reducing development cycle time to 25 % of original, 15% budget reduction while delivering to product scope, quality, and managing risk and critical paths
- Managed a team of Hardware Development and Product Validation Engineers to launch brand new product lines including Compute eXpress Link, Non Volatile Random Access Memory, Storage accelerators and launching products ranging from 3-6 month development
- · Optimized report Turnaround time using Lean and Six Sigma, and Agile reducing review and handover, and context switching time required to 12.5% of original
- Defined, created and deployed end-to-end workflows using JIRA, and Smartsheet systems and successfully eliminated scope creep, and process oversights
- Developed and continuously improved process, benchmarking documents and qualification reports using MS Visio, and Confluence based on process and organizational document control flows to ensure integration to ISO compliant requirements to ensure effectiveness, reliability and efficient scaling of Cross Functional Team systems across the organization
- Organized and implemented regular design and quality reviews with Software, Equipment and Hardware vendors customers ensuring projects and timelines are measured and managed accurately. Leading into delivery of 8 successful technical programs with over \$ 10 million in revenue
- Drove Customer, Engineering, Marketing, Supply Chain, and Operations during Design and new product introduction engineers, build work flows to effectively communicate requirements and resolve technical conflicts ensuring program health
- Managed firmware release and qualification by maintaining release notes, errata, Engineering Change Notifications through development and coordinating Product Control Notifications to customers as required
- Ensured stakeholder accountability and task visibility with regular project plan review, cross functional team meetings, follow-ups, escalations
- Prompt engineered with AI tools such as Google Bard and Open AI Chat GPT to speed up creating and reviewing Legal, Engineering and Product Marketing Collateral reducing cycle time from 2 weeks to few days

Sr. Technical Program Manager, Process Engineer

Aug. 2018 - Jun. 2022

SMART Modular Technologies

Newark, CA

- Delivered OEM NPI non-volaitile programs total of \$10 million in sales for specialty memory business unit
- Managed cross functional projects in matrix organization covering range of areas to provide network connectivity to developing areas worldwide
- Achieved overall 29% cycle time reduction by implementing ground-up JIRA frameworks and 'one-step-ahead' meetings across multiple cross-functional teams
- Scheduled, risk and change management on different NPI accounts related to product design in coordination with various engineering management
- Implemented effective program communication and visibility to all internal and external stakeholders
- Championed program management, lean six-sigma and operational excellence, also establishing metrics for measuring performance and improvements in these areas

Process and Quality Assurance Engineer

Aug. 2018 - Jun. 2022

SMART Modular Technologies

Newark, CA

Education

Master of Science: Industrial and Systems Engineering

State University of New York at Binghamton

Bachelor of Technology

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

Binghamton, NY

New Delhi, India